Two worlds. One home.
Warcraft is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Duncan Jones.
The peaceful realm of Azeroth stands on the brink of war as its civilization faces a fearsome
race of invaders: orc warriors fleeing their dying home to colonize another.
As a portal opens to connect the two worlds, one army faces
destruction and the other faces extinction.
From opposing sides, two heroes are set on a collision course that will
decide the fate of their family, their people, and their home.
Commander Anduin Lothar, played by Travis Fimmel.
Garona Halforcen, played by Paula Patton.
Medivh (Guardian), played by Ben Foster.
King Llane Wrynn, played by Dominic Cooper.
Khadgar, played by Ben Schnetzer.
Durotan / Antonidas, played by Toby Kebbell.
Warcraft  (alternatively known as Warcraft: The Beginning) is a 2016 American
action fantasy film based on the video game series of the same name.
Directed by Duncan Jones, who co-wrote with Charles Leavitt, it stars Travis Fimmel, Paula Patton, Ben
Foster, Dominic Cooper, Toby Kebbell, Ben Schnetzer, Robert Kazinsky, and Daniel Wu.
The film follows Anduin Lothar of Stormwind and Durotan of the Frostwolf clan as heroes set on opposite sides of
a growing war, as the warlock Gul'dan leads the Horde to invade Azeroth using a magic portal.
Together, a few human heroes and dissenting Orcs must attempt to
stop the true evil behind this war and restore peace.
The film was first announced in 2006 as a project partnership between
Legendary Pictures and the game's developer, Blizzard Entertainment.
Warcraft premiered in Paris on May 24, 2016, and was released by
Universal Pictures in the United States on June 10, 2016.
The film grossed $439 million worldwide against a production budget of $160 million,
becoming the highest-grossing film based on a video game at the time.
However, it failed to reach its break-even point of $450–500
million after global marketing and distribution.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, though
fans of the Warcraft franchise were kinder to it.
The film explores themes of elves, dwarf, magic, betrayal, king.